# **Manaar Salama**

mgasalama@gmail.com | (209) 938-8519 | linkedin.com/in/mgsalama | mgsalama.github.io U.S. Citizen | she/her/hers

## **SUMMARY**

Data Science Senior graduating May 2024. 3+ years of experience using Python and its relevant data science packages, SQL, and R from on-campus job and personal projects. Utilized CRM analytics platform and implemented effective BI dashboards during Scenthound internship. Seeking full-time data analyst position to start after graduation.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Berkeley

May 2024

B.A. in Data Science, with specialization in Economics. Minor in Chinese.

GPA: 3.68 / 4.00

Coursework: Data Mining and Analytics; Econometrics; Principles & Techniques of Data Science; Data Structures

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python (pandas, Plotly, Keras, scikit-learn), Java, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), MongoDB, R, HTML, Tableau, PowerBI, Jupyter Notebooks, Snowflake, AWS, Jira, GitHub, Excel / Google Sheets (VLOOKUP, PivotTables, INDEX/MATCH)

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Jupyter Notebook Developer**

January 2022 - Present

UC Berkeley's Division of Computing, Data Science, and Society

Berkeley, CA

- Develop Jupyter Notebook data science and machine learning projects as a student employee for 8+ courses
- Lead 6 teams of 3-4 students to write 15+ module notebooks in Python, SQL, and R to date
- Work alongside professors and supervisors to devise pedagogical plans for incorporating data science concepts

Data Science Intern

June 2023 - August 2023

Scenthound

Jupiter, FL (Remote)

- Created the company's first PowerBI dashboards for aggregation and visualization of data on dog health records
- Wrote SQL queries to backfill missing information from 30,000+ rows regarding appointments and sales insights
- Designed 3 reports with Zoho Analytics CRM for exploring sales, resulting in 100+ transactions of interest

## **Machine Learning Committee Co-Chair**

August 2022 - December 2022

Women in Computing and Data Science at UC Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

- Co-taught 14 female-identifying students introductory concepts of machine learning with Python packages
- Advised students in creating first machine learning projects that were presented at a club-wide showcase
- Collaborated with a team of 10 officers to hold professional and social events for 30+ club members

Academic Intern January 2021 - December 2022

Computer Science 10 (Beauty and Joy of Computing) at UC Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

- Facilitated labs of 30+ students with TAs by teaching introductory coding concepts in Python for lab assignments
- Developed 3 chapters of course's online textbook and coding examples in a smaller group of staff members
- Supervised 4+ teams of students in completing projects by fixing Python and Jupyter Notebook related issues

## **PROJECTS & CERTIFICATIONS**

**Canadian Wind Turbine Analysis:** Built Jupyter Notebook using pandas and Plotly for cleaning and analyzing data on wind energy. Designed 4+ Tableau visualizations and a dashboard with cleaned data to present actionable next steps for development in production and efficiency of wind turbines in Canada to an audience of simulated stakeholders.

**Hierarchical, Linear, and Nonparametric Modeling:** Formulated hierarchical and ML models to generate accurate cardiovascular disease prediction and robust mortality rate estimation with Python's PyMC and scikit-learn.

**Certifications:** Google Analytics 4